# 拍成小饼 把馅心抹上
Pat them into small pieces, and put on the paste
# 就这样给它扔在里头
Just dip it in like that
# 外宾们觉得特别爽口
The foreign guests think it’s a tasty and refreshing dessert
# 吃了一盘以后又要一盘
They kept ordering more
# 做一个江米凉果
Let’s make a Jiang Mi Liang Guo ( glutinous rice cake with paste*)
# 过去这就是北京的小吃
This is a dessert in Beijing from the past
# 家里头特别好做
Super easy to make at home
# 很简单 有青红丝 有京糕
It’s easy, and you just need some green and red strips made with citrus peels, Beijing haw jelly
# 有芝麻 有砂糖 还有面粉 豆沙
Sesame, sugar, flours and sweetened red bean paste
# 把江米我们已经泡上了
Steep glutinous rice in water
# 应该泡两个小时左右
For about two hours
# 现在先把这蒸上 这个已经泡完了
Now we are going to put it on steam
# 我们淘一淘 我们搁的是半斤的糯米
Let’s wash them, and we used half jin ( jin = 500g) glutinous rice
# 我们找这样一平盘
Let’s find a flat plate
# 它受热面积（大） 它好蒸
With bigger heating area it will be steamed faster
# 把这个米搁在这里头
Put the glutinous rice into it
# 不能有糟蹋
Can’t waste any
# 这个我们用三百克左右的水
Let’s use about 300g water
# 这样（用平盘）成熟的快
It’s faster to cook with a flat plate
# 锅开了啊 蒸二十分钟左右就行了
Water is boiled, now just steam it for 20 mins
# 这个也是（水开后）开开盖
Same with this one, take off the lid after the water is boiled
# 干屉布搁在里头 干蒸 要干蒸
Put a dry sheet of cloth in the pot , then dry steam
# 之后我们把面粉给它搁在里头 四两左右
We put about 4 Liang ( 0.2 kg) flours in it
# 干蒸面粉 主要是让它当这个薄面
It has to be dry steamed to be the thin layer outside
# 因为咱们这个是马上制完了就能吃的
Because this one we can eat it right after making it
# 直接入口的 所以我们必须得蒸熟了面
We have to make sure it’s cooked after steaming, so we can eat it directly
# 用生面就不行了
Do not use flours that’s not steamed
# 这个蒸多长时间呢 这个有一刻钟就可以了
Steam it with about 15 mins
# 一个二十分钟 一个一刻钟 对
The other one was 20 mins, and this one is 15 mins. Yes
# 这个青红丝是老北京的
These green and red strips made with citrus peels is a Beijing old tradition
# 一种当配头当配色用的
That you use for color dressing
# 做沙琪玛 自来红都要搁上青红丝
It’s used when making Sha Qi Ma and Moon Cake
# 下一步咱们给它改刀 切了
Next, we are going to cut them
# 切细致点改 切成末
Mince them finely
# 没有青红丝 我就劝大家买点果料
If you don’t have these strips at home, I would advise you to buy some dry fruit ingredients
# 什么颜色都有
With all different kinds of colors
# 这个青红丝咱们都给改改刀
Now we mince all of these strips
# （青红丝）味道好吃 就是用橘皮制作的
They taste great, and they are made by citrus peels
# 原来我们做的时候 尤其夏天
Before when we make this, especially during summer
# 外宾们出去旅游 回来的时候
When the foreign guests come back from outside
# 我们就给他端一盘这个
We will serve them this dessert
# 吃了一盘又要一盘
And they kept ordering more
# 觉得特别爽口 特别清凉
Because it’s tasty and refreshing
# 再有就是搁点京糕 就是山楂糕
Plus, you should put some haw jelly in
# 也切成小颗粒 我跟我徒弟也说
Dice them to small pieces, that’s what I always tell my student
# 不管做什么你做细就好
Anything you do, just make sure every part is done to the smallest detail
# 把芝麻 砂糖搁在里头
Put sesame and sugar in it
# 这芝麻一定焙熟 炒熟
The sesame has to be baked
# 另外咱们搁上青红丝
Now we put the green and red citrus strips in
# 颜色就好看了 五颜六色的
The colors are great, very colorful
# 再把这京糕丁搁在里头 打散
Now put the haw jelly dices in to it and mix in
# 这个就可以了
Now it is done
# 差不多了 关火
Almost, let’s turn the fire
# 这（江米）米饭蒸的
The glutinous rice is cooked
# 这个让它凉一凉
Let it chill for a bit
# 这个咱们也蒸熟了 兜出来
The flours are cooked too, take them out
# 给它团团 熟的面粉
Mix the
# 咱们研一研 过箩
# 干蒸完了之后过过小箩 成面粉
# 我们拿这个当薄面
# 再有用咱们的矿泉水 把布给它浸泡
# 因为咱们直接入口的
Because we are going to eat it directly from it
# 各位网友们别不在乎 一定讲究卫生
We should pay attention to food hygiene when making it
# 咱们下一步你瞧
Here’s the next step
# 把咱们蒸好的江米 搁在这儿
Let’s put the glutinous rice here
# 真黏糊
So sticky
# 用这个（湿的）豆包布 碾压
Grind it within this wet cloth
# 我又跟您学一小窍门
I just learned another trick from you
# 也让人看见有米粒 似有似无的
Keep some rice still shaped
# 大功就告成了 你看
Now it’s done, you see
# 这个就把咱们刚才弄的面
Now here’s the flours we steamed
# 千万不能搁生面
Do NOT use flours that are not steamed
# 完了之后把这个倒在里头
Pour them in after
# 这基本上就行了
It’s almost done
# 这夏天摆一盘儿  那叫舒服
It’s great to eat a plate during summer time
# 吃一口是一口啊 吃了这口想下口
You would want to keep eating it nonstop
# 行了 搓成条
Ok, rub it into a strip
# 这个咱们做成小剂儿
And we split it into small parts
# 这个馅儿咱们随便弄 多种多样
You can customize the paste in any way you like
# 能做好多种
There’s many ways
# 做完了之后就好办了 撒点熟面
After that it’s easy, just sprinkle some cooked flours onto it
# 这个就开始做了
Now we are making it
# 各网友回去立竿见影 因为家里头特别好做
Everyone can just make it after watching this video, and it’s easy to make
# 不是说多难的
It’s not super hard
# 你看揪完小剂儿就这样拍成小饼
After you split them into parts, pat them into a small round shaped cake
# 把馅儿心抹上
Put the paste in
# 就这样给它扔在里头
Just dip it in like that
# 就用三个手指头
Only use 3 fingers
# 三个手指头一掐 它就粘上了
Pinch with three fingers to stick the dressing on
# 你看看五颜六色的 漂亮 真好看
It’s colorful, so pretty
# 王师傅做东西都不用装饰
Chef Wang doesn’t do dressing when making them
# 这省事 但是一定要要求卫生
It’s easy, but you have to pay attention to food hygiene
# 就让它立即挺起来
Let it straighten up immediately
# 有的做来做去就倒了
Some fell during the process
# 不能让它倒 让它直着
It can’t be fell on one side, make it straight
# 让它直着 这样才好看
We have to make sure it’s straight, so it looks nice
# 中间再来一个 就行了
Plus another one in the middle
# 这叫什么 江米凉果 凉的啊
What’s it called? Jiang Mi Liang Guo? It’s cold.
# 过去这就是北京的小吃
This is a dessert in Beijing from the past
# 这一捏你瞧 省事儿 OK 了
Just shape it like this, it’s easy, OK
# 行了 下冰箱
It’s good. Now we put it into the fridge.
# 还真凉
It’s pretty cold
# 王师傅给接过来了
Wang Shi Fu passed it over here
# 行么 不是行吗 真好看
Is it good? Yea it looks awesome.
# 我觉着这个凉着特别好吃
I love it when it’s cold
# 一镇凉了它也挺实了
It’s pretty solid after it’s chilled
# 这个口感我们要求 糯米一定要软糯
We ask that the glutinous rice has to be soft and chewy
# 京糕的酸甜 芝麻的香
The sweet and sour taste of the haw jelly and fragrant of the sesame
# 另外我们还有砂糖
We also got the sugar
# 吃起来咔吱咔吱的
Which is crunchy
# 而且有芝麻吃起来也嚼得越来越香
And the sesame gives it a special fragrant when you chew it
# 所以这个夏天吃着特别的凉爽
So it’s very refreshing for summer
# 看着就好吃
Looks delicious
# 你先给大大爷来一口
Let Da Da Ye try it first
# 大爷尝  我不要
Da Ye Try it, I don’t want to
# 我们这是尊敬长辈
We are showing respect to elders
# 大爷给了我没法给了
I can’t do it after Da ye did it already
# 二伯你先来
Er bai you go first
# 我来一块
Let me try one
# 吃着砂糖了么 咔吱咔吱
Did you hear the sugar when chewing it?
# 我尝尝
Let me try it
# 真香 外边糯 里边的果料
Smells amazing, it has a soft glut shell with fruit ingredients
# 加上豆沙馅的那种糯香
Plus the of fragrant of the sweetened red bean paste
# 比粽子好吃
It’s better than Zong Zi （traditional Chinese rice-pudding）
# 谢谢大大爷 谢谢二伯 谢谢大爷
Thank you Da da ye, Er Bai, thank you Da ye
# 大大爷辛苦了
Da da ye did a great job